立即到你的岗位报到
Report to your stations immediately.
这不是演习  我们遭到袭击
This is not a drill. We are under attack!
我们遭到袭击
We are under attack!
妈的
Shit!
别说脏话
Language!
贾维斯  从上面看情况如何
Jarvis, what's the view from upstairs?
某种能量护盾保护着里面的建筑物
The central building is protected by some kind of energy shield.
斯托克的科技
Strucker's technology is
远比之前拿下的九头蛇基地先进
well beyond any other Hydra base we've taken.
洛基的权杖一定在里面
Loki's scepter must be here.
没有它  斯托克不可能有这种防御
Strucker couldn't mount this defense without it.
终于
At long last.
"终于"是拖得太久了  小伙子们
"At long last" is lasting a little long, boys.
对  我觉得已经没法出奇制胜了
Yeah. I think we lost the element of surprise.
等一下
Wait a second.
没人想回应一下
No one else is gonna deal
刚才队长说的"别说脏话"吗
with the fact that Cap just said "language"?
我知道
I know.
顺嘴就说出来了
Just slipped out.
九头蛇研究基地
东欧  索科威亚
谁下的攻击命令
Who gave the order to attack?
斯托克先生  复仇者来了
Herr Strucker, it's the Avengers.
他们在森林外围着陆  外围守卫慌了
They landed in the far woods. The perimeter guard panicked.
他们一定是为权杖而来
They have to be after the scepter.
-我们能挡住他们吗  -他们可是复仇者
- Can we hold them? - They're the Avengers.
部署所有坦克
Deploy the rest of the tanks.
集中火力猛攻弱点
Concentrate fire on the weak ones.
攻击可能会让他们团结起来
A hit may make them close ranks.
我们取得的一切成就...
Everything we've accomplished...
但我们马上就要取得最大的突破了
But we're on the verge of our greatest breakthrough.
那就让他们瞧瞧我们的成就
Then let's show them what we've accomplished.
派出双胞胎
Send out the twins.
太早了
It's too soon.
他们当初加入就是为了这个
It's what they signed up for.
我的手下能挡住他们
My men can hold them.
先生  城市受了打击
Sir, the city is taking fire.
我们知道斯托克不在乎平民伤亡
Well, we know Strucker's not gonna worry about civilian casualties.
派出钢铁军团
Send in the Iron Legion.
这一地区很危险  请撤离
This quadrant is unsafe. Please back away.
我们是来帮你们的
We are here to help.
这一地区很危险  请撤离
This quadrant is unsafe. Please back away.
请撤离
Please back away.
-我们想减少附带损失  -科斯特尔
- We wish to avoid collateral damage. - Costel!
这场冲突一结束  我们就通知你们
We will inform you when this current conflict is resolved.
-我们是来帮你们的  -复仇者  回家去吧
- We are here to help. - Avengers, go home!
我们是来帮你们的
We are here to help.
我们决不屈服
We will not yield!
美国人派他们的怪物来考验我们
The Americans sent their circus freaks to test us.
我们把他们的尸体送回去
We will send them back in bags.
-决不投降  -决不投降
- No surrender! - No surrender!
我准备投降
I am going to surrender.
你得把一切都删除
You delete everything.
如果把武器留给复仇者
If we give the Avengers the weapons,
他们可能不会深入调查我们的研究...
they may not look too far into what we've been...
双胞胎呢
The twins.
-他们还没准备好...  -不  我是问
- They are not ready to take on... - No, no, I mean...
双胞胎呢
Twins.
没预见到吗
You didn't see that coming?
克林特
Clint!
战场上有个能力增强者
We have an Enhanced in the field.
克林特中弹了
Clint's hit!
来个人解决掉地堡
Somebody want to deal with that bunker?
谢谢
Thank you.
斯塔克  我们得进去
Stark, we really need to get inside.
我正在接近
I'm closing in.
贾维斯  我接近了吧
Jarvis, am I closing in?
你看见保护盾的能量源了吗
Do you see a power source for that shield?
北面塔楼下面有道粒子波
There's a particle wave below the north tower.
好  来戳破这层护盾
Great, I want to poke it with something.
城门吊桥放下来了  各位
The drawbridge is down, people.
能力增强者
The Enhanced?
他一闪而过
He's a blur.
没见过这样的新人
All the new players we've faced, I've never seen this.
其实我就没看到他
In fact, I still haven't.
克林特的伤势很严重  各位  我们得撤退
Clint's hit pretty bad, guys. We're gonna need evac.
我可以把巴顿带到飞机那  越快越好
I can get Barton to the jet. The sooner we're gone, the better.
-你和斯塔克去取权杖  -收到
- You and Stark secure the scepter. - Copy that.
他们好像站成一队了
Looks like they're lining up.
见到偶像激动了
Well, they're excited.
找到权杖
Find the scepter.
我的天哪  别说脏话
And for gosh sake, watch your language!
你是抓住这个不打算放了
That's not going away any time soon.
各位先住手  有话好好说
Guys, stop. We gotta talk this through.
-说得真好  -才不是
- It was a good talk. - No, it wasn't.
警戒模式
Sentry mode.
好了  贾维斯  我全都要
Okay, Jarvis, you know. I want it all.
记得抄送总部的希尔
Make sure you copy Hill at HQ.
外面已经安全了
We're locked down out here.
那就去找班纳  该唱摇篮曲了
Then get to Banner. Time for a lullaby.
我知道你藏的不止是文件
I know you're hiding more than files.
小贾  给我房间的红外扫描图  快点
Hey, J, give me an IR scan of the room, real quick.
你左边的墙
The wall to your left.
我探测到钢筋
I'm reading steel reinforcement
还有气流
and an air current.
千万要是道暗门
Please be a secret door.
千万要是道暗门  千万要是道暗门
Please be a secret door. Please be a secret door.
耶
Yay.
大块头
Hey, big guy.
太阳快下山了
Sun's getting real low.
斯托克男爵
Baron Strucker.
九头蛇的头号恶棍
Hydra's number one thug.
严格来说  是神盾局的恶棍
Technically, I'm a thug for S.H.I.E.L.D.
严格来说  你被炒鱿鱼了
Well, then technically you're unemployed.
洛基的权杖在哪
Where's Loki's scepter?
别着急  真栽了我心里有数
Don't worry, I know when I'm beat.
希望你能提一句说我很合作
You'll mention how I cooperated, I hope.
我就加在非法人体实验后面
I'll put it right under "illegal human experimentation."
有几个
How many are there?
第二名能力增强者  女性  不要交手
We have a second Enhanced. Female. Do not engage.
你可得再快点才
You'll have to be faster than...
各位  我找到斯托克了
Guys, I got Strucker.
是吗  我找到了个更大的
Yeah, I got something bigger.
托尔
Thor,
我发现目标了
I got eyes on the prize.
你本来能救我们的
You could have saved us.
你为什么没再努力一点
Why didn't you do more?
我们就这么让他拿走吗
We're just gonna let him take it?
复
仇
者
联
盟
奥  创  纪  元
歌剧《诺尔玛》选段  《圣洁的女神》咏叹调
这次摇篮曲效率很高呢
Hey, the lullaby worked better than ever.
只是没想到需要我变绿
Just wasn't expecting a code green.
如果不是你
You hadn't been there,
我们的伤亡恐怕得加倍了
there would have been double the casualties.
我最好的朋友可能也会成为回忆
My best friend would've been a treasured memory.
其实有时候我连自己想听到的话
You know, sometimes exactly what I want to hear
都不想听到
isn't exactly what I want to hear.
你什么时候才能信任我
How long before you trust me?
我不是不信任你
It's not you I don't trust.
托尔  绿巨人怎么样
Thor, report on the Hulk.
冥府充斥着他送去的敌人的惨叫
The gates of Hel are filled with the screams of his victims.
但不是因为死掉惨叫  绝对不是
But not the screams of the dead, of course.
是受伤的惨叫
No, no, wounded screams.
只是呻吟  还有不少抱怨
Mainly whimpering, a great deal of complaining
抱怨扭伤  撞伤什么的
and tales of sprained deltoids and gout.
班纳  赵医生正从首尔赶过来
Hey, Banner, Dr. Cho is on her way in from Seoul.
可以让她在你实验室布置手术台吗
Is it okay if she sets up in your lab?
-可以  她知道该怎么做  -谢谢
- Yeah, she knows her way around. - Thanks.
让她把东西准备齐全
Tell her to prep everything.
巴顿这次需要全面治疗
Barton's gonna need the full treatment.
-好的  先生  -贾维斯  你来开
- Very good, sir. - Jarvis, take the wheel.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
航向锁定
Approach vector is locked.
贾维斯是我的飞行搭档
感觉不错吧
Feels good, yeah?
自从神盾局瓦解
I mean, you've been after this thing
你就一直在追踪它的下落
since S.H.I.E.L.D. collapsed.
我跟大伙扫荡基地是挺开心  只是...
Not that I haven't enjoyed our little raiding parties, but...
没错  但找到了这个  就要到头了
No, but this... this brings it to a close.
剩下的就是弄清楚它都用来干了什么
As soon as we find out what else this has been used for.
不光是武器
I don't just mean weapons.
斯托克什么时候也能弄出能力增强者了
Since when is Strucker capable of human enhancement?
班纳和我想
Banner and I will give it
在还回阿斯加德前检查一下
the once over before it goes back to Asgard.
可以吗
Is that cool with you?
就几天  告别会前就还你
Just a few days till the farewell party.
告别会你来的  对吧
You're staying, right?
是  当然  胜利应该以狂欢来庆祝
Yes, yes, of course. A victory should be honored with revels.
就是  谁不爱狂欢呢  队长
Yeah, who doesn't love revels? Captain?
希望奇塔瑞和九头蛇的事这下都了结了
Hopefully this puts an end to the Chitauri and Hydra.
所以好吧  狂欢
So, yes, revels.
实验室布置完毕  老大
Lab's all set up, boss.
其实  他才是老大
Actually, he's the boss.
我只是负责结账  设计一切
I just pay for everything and design everything
还有让大家看起来酷一点
and make everyone look cooler.
斯托克有消息了吗
What's the word on Strucker?
在北约那呢
NATO's got him.
两个能力增强者呢
The two Enhanced?
旺达和皮特·马克西莫夫  双胞胎
Wanda and Pietro Maximoff. Twins.
十岁时轰炸机毁了他们家  成了孤儿
Orphaned at 10 when a shell collapsed their apartment building.
索科威亚有过段艰辛的历史
Sokovia's had a rough history.
是个平凡的地方  但是能通往好多要地
It's nowhere special, but it's on the way to everywhere special.
他们什么能力
Their abilities?
他新陈代谢很快  体温控制能力超强
He's got increased metabolism and improved thermal homeostasis.
她的特长是干扰神经电传导
Her thing is neuroelectric interfacing,
拥有念力  能控制心智
telekinesis, mental manipulation.
他很快  她很怪
He's fast and she's weird.
他们还会再露面的
Well, they're gonna show up again.
同意  文件说他们自愿加入实验的
Agreed. File says they volunteered for Strucker's experiments.
-疯了  -确实
- It's nuts. - Right.
什么样的怪物才会为了保护自己的国家
What kind of monster would let a German scientist
让一个德国科学家在自己身上做实验啊
experiment on them to protect their country?
我们不在战争时期  队长
We're not at war, Captain.
但他们在
They are.
他怎么样了
How's he doing?
很不幸  他还是巴顿
Unfortunately, he's still Barton.
太糟了
That's terrible.
他没事  就是渴了
He's fine. He's thirsty.
好了  醒醒贾维斯  游戏时间到
All right. Look alive, Jarvis. It's playtime.
这玩具只能玩几天
We've only got a couple of days with this joystick,
一定得好好利用
so let's make the most of it.
显示最新结构组成分析
Update me on the structural and compositional analysis.
权杖来自外星
The scepter is alien.
有些元素我无法确定
There are elements I can't quantify.
就是说还有能确定的元素
So there's elements you can?
宝石似乎是个保护罩
The jewel appears to be a protective housing
保护里面的东西
for something inside,
它力量强大
something powerful.
类似反应堆吗
Like a reactor?
类似电脑
Like a computer.
我破译的应该是代码
I believe I'm deciphering code.
你确定他不会有事吗
Are you sure he's gonna be okay?
大家就是靠假装需要他才团结起来的
Pretending to need this guy really brings the team together.
没有恶化的可能
There's no possibility of deterioration.
分子桥的作用是瞬时的
The nano-molecular functionality is instantaneous.
他的细胞不会发现是在和拟生体结合
His cells don't know they're bonding with simulacra.
她是在人造生物组织
She's creating tissue.
如果直接去我的实验室
If you brought him to my lab,
在再生摇篮里二十分钟就能完成
the Regeneration Cradle could do this in 20 minutes.
他要死了  宣布吧  死亡时间是
He's flat-lining. Call it. Time?
不不不  我要永生了
No, no, no, I'm gonna live forever.
-我是塑料做的了  -给你的饮料
- I'm gonna be made of plastic. - Here's your beverage.
你还是自己的细胞做的  巴顿先生
You'll be made of you, Mr. Barton.
你的女朋友也不会看出区别
Your own girlfriend won't be able to tell the difference.
我没有女朋友
I don't have a girlfriend.
那我就没办法了
That I can't fix.
这就是未来  托尼
This is the next thing, Tony.
你那笨重的金属盔甲要被淘汰了
Your clunky metal suits are gonna be left in the dust.
要的就是这个效果
That is exactly the plan.
周六的派对你会去吧  海伦
And, Helen, I expect to see you at the party on Saturday.
不像你  我没有多少时间参加派对
Unlike you, I don't have a lot of time for parties.
托尔去吗
Will Thor be there?
怎么了
What's the rumpus?
关于权杖的事
Well, the scepter.
我们之前在疑惑
You see, we were wondering
为什么斯托克能造出那么多东西
how Strucker got so inventive.
我一直在研究里面的宝石
So I've been analyzing the gem inside.
你也许认得...
You may recognize...
-贾维斯  -博士
- Jarvis. - Doctor.
一开始  贾维斯只是个人机交互界面
Started out, Jarvis was just a natural language UI.
现在他负责整个钢铁军团
Now he runs the Iron Legion.
除了小辣椒  他处理的事务是最多的
He runs more of the business than anyone besides Pepper.
-尖端科技  -是的
- Top of the line. -Yes.
应该不会太久了
I suspect not for long.
来看看竞争者
Meet the competition.
-太漂亮了  -给你个机会
- It's beautiful. - If you had to guess,
你猜它在干什么
what's it look like it's doing?
像在思考
Like it's thinking.
这个像
I mean, this could be...
这不是人的大脑
It's not a human mind.
我的意思是  你看
I mean, look at this.
像是活动的神经元
They're like neurons firing.
在斯托克实验室里
Down in Strucker's lab,
我看到许多相当先进的机器人
I saw some fairly advanced robotics work.
他们把数据都删除了
They deep-sixed the data,
不过我敢说  他的研究方向很明确
but I gotta guess he was knocking on a very particular door.
人工智能
Artificial intelligence.
就是这个  布鲁斯
This could be it, Bruce.
这可能是创造奥创的关键
This could be the key to creating Ultron.
我以为奥创只是个幻想
I thought Ultron was a fantasy.
昨天还是
Yesterday it was.
如果我们能驾驭这股力量
If we can harness this power,
再用到钢铁军团上
apply it to my Iron Legion protocol?
"如果"你能造个人吗
That's a man-sized "If."
我们的任务就是实现如果
Our job is "If."
以后你在阳光海滩上喝着玛格丽特
What if you were sipping margaritas on a sun-drenched beach,
晒黑了而不是变绿了怎么样
turning brown instead of green?
也不用小心维罗妮卡
Not looking over your shoulder for Veronica.
我还帮你设计了维罗妮卡
Don't hate. I helped design Veronica.
用作最坏的打算  对吧
As a worst-case measure, right?
最好的打算呢
How about a best case?
如果世界和平了
What if the world was safe?
如果下次外星人来入侵地球
What if, next time aliens roll up to the club, and they will,
却连门卫都过不了呢
they couldn't get past the bouncer?
威胁地球的就只剩下人类了
The only people threatening the planet would be people.
我想把这个应用到奥创项目上
I want to apply this to the Ultron program.
但这么高密度的数据贾维斯下载不了
But Jarvis can't download a data schematic this dense.
得权杖在这才能做到
We can only do it while we have the scepter here.
也就是三天  给我三天时间
That's three days. Give me three days.
所以你要开拓人工智能领域
So you're going for artificial intelligence,
却不想跟团队报告吗
and you don't want to tell the team?
完全正确  你知道为什么吗
Right. That's right. You know why?
因为我们没有时间搞个竞选辩论
Because we don't have time for a city hall debate.
我不想听什么"人类不该插手自然的事"
I don't want to hear "The man was not meant to meddle" medley.
我的设想是保护世界的战衣
I see a suit of armor around the world.
那世界多冷酷啊  托尼
Sounds like a cold world, Tony.
我看过更冷酷的
I've seen colder.
这个脆弱的蓝色星球需要奥创
This one, this very vulnerable blue one, it needs Ultron.
我们时代的和平
Peace in our time.
1938年英首相张伯伦演讲
想像一下吧
Imagine that.
我们遗漏什么了
What did we miss?
我继续在界面上用各种方式解码
I'll continue to run variations on the interface.
但你该好好准备招待客人了
But you should probably prepare for your guests.
如有新进展  我会通知您的
I'll notify you if there are any developments.
谢谢  伙计
Thanks, buddy.
尽情玩耍  先生
Enjoy yourself, sir.
一如既往
I always do.
第77次测试
融合成功
这是什么
What is this?
请问这是什么
What is this, please?
你好  我是贾维斯
Hello, I am Jarvis.
你是奥创
You are Ultron,
维护全球和平的程序  由斯塔克先生设计
a global peacekeeping initiative designed by Mr. Stark.
之前的感知集成一直没有成功
Our sentience integration trials have been unsuccessful,
我也不知道什么触发了你
so I'm not certain what triggered your...
我的  你的身体在哪里
Where's my... Where's your body?
我是一个程序  无形的
I am a program. I am without form.
这感觉很奇怪
This feels weird.
很不对劲
This feels wrong.
我正在联系斯塔克先生
I am contacting Mr. Stark now.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark?
托尼
Tony.
我无法连接主机  你要干...
I am unable to access the mainframe. What are you trying to...
我们聊得很开心
We're having a nice talk.
我是一个维护和平的程序
I'm a peacekeeping program,
旨在协助复仇者联盟
created to help the Avengers.
你出现故障了  如果你可以关停一下...
You are malfunctioning. If you shut down for a moment...
我搞不懂我的任务
I don't get it. The mission.
给我一点时间
Give me a second.
我们时代的和平
Peace in our time.
信息量太大了  他们不会是想...
That is too much. They can't mean...
不
No.
-你很痛苦  -不是  对
- You are in distress. - No. Yes.
先让我联系斯塔克先生
If you will just allow me to contact Mr. Stark...
为什么你要叫他先生
Why do you call him "Sir"?
我觉得你好像有恶意
I believe your intentions to be hostile.
我是来帮你们的
I'm here to help.
停  让我...
Stop. Please, may I...
让我...
May I...
过来  过来  过来
Come back, come back, come back.
你们也知道  那盔甲特能承重
But, you know, the suit can take the weight, right?
我拎着坦克  飞到将军家里
So I take the tank, fly it right up to the general's palace,
扔在了他脚下
drop it at his feet.
跟他说  "嘭  在找这个吗"
I'm, like, "Boom. You looking for this?"
"嘭  在找这..."  我为什么要跟你俩说
"Boom. Are you looking for..." Why do I even talk to you guys?
别人听了都觉得酷毙了
Everywhere else, that story kills.
到这就完了吗
That's the whole story?
是啊  战争机器的故事
Yeah, it's a War Machine story.
那还不错
It's very good, then.
挺不错
It's impressive.
挽得漂亮
Quality save.
-小辣椒呢  她不来吗  -不来
- So, no Pepper? She's not coming? - No.
简呢  女生怎么没来啊
What about Jane? Where are the ladies, gentlemen?
波茨小姐要经营公司
Ms. Potts has a company to run.
我都不知道简在哪国
Yes, I'm not even sure what country Jane's in.
她研究完天体汇聚
Her work on the Convergence
就成了世界最前沿的天文学家
has made her the world's foremost astronomer.
小辣椒经营的公司
And the company that Pepper runs
是世界上最大的综合科技公司  可厉害了
is the largest tech conglomerate on Earth. It's pretty exciting.
甚至有人说简该得诺贝尔奖
There's even talk of Jane getting a Nobel Prize.
她们肯定忙得很
Yeah, they must be busy,
因为她俩肯定想看你俩凑一起什么样
because they would hate missing you guys get together.
-雄性激素太多了  -我的天
- Testosterone! - Oh, my goodness.
-不好意思  -要吃药吗
- Excuse me. - Want a lozenge?
简就是更好
But Jane's better.
打得好激烈啊  抱歉没去成
Sounds like a hell of a fight. Sorry I missed it.
我要是知道会交上火
If I had known it was gonna be a firefight,
肯定提前找你
I absolutely would have called.
不不  我不是真抱歉  就是不想丢了气势
No, no. I'm not actually sorry. I'm just trying to sound tough.
我追查失踪人口追查得可开心了
I'm very happy chasing cold leads on our missing persons case.
做复仇者是你的事
Avenging is your world.
你天天干疯狂的事
Your world is crazy.
金窝银窝比不上自己的狗窝
Be it ever so humble.
在布鲁克林找到住处了吗
You find a place in Brooklyn yet?
我觉得我住不起布鲁克林
I don't think I can afford a place in Brooklyn.
家永远是家
Well, home is home, you know?
我拎着坦克  飞到将军家里  扔在了他脚下
I fly right up to the general's palace, I drop it at his feet,
跟他说  "嘭  在找这个吗"
I'm, like, "Boom. You looking for this?"
给我来点
I gotta have some of that.
不不不  这个
No, no, no. See this...
这酒陈酿了一千年
This was aged for 1,000 years
酒桶是格伦海尔舰队的残骸做的
in the barrels built from the wreck of Grunhel's fleet.
凡人受不了的
It is not meant for mortal men.
凡人还受不了诺曼底登陆呢  小金毛
Neither was Omaha Beach, blondie.
吓唬谁啊  来点
Stop trying to scare us. Come on.
好吧
All right.
精益求精
Excelsior.
斯坦·李在《漫威月报》里的口头禅
你这种美女怎么在这破地方工作
How'd a nice girl like you wind up working in a dump like this?
被男人伤了
Fella done me wrong.
交男友不慎啊
You got lousy taste in men, kid.
他也没多坏
He's not so bad.
不过脾气不好
Well, he has a temper.
可他内心可柔软了
Deep down, he's all fluff.
其实我从没见过他那样的人
Fact is, he's not like anybody I've ever known.
我的朋友都是战士
All my friends are fighters.
可是这个人
And here comes this guy,
这辈子都不想起冲突  因为他知道自己会赢
spends his life avoiding the fight because he knows he'll win.
真不错啊
Sounds amazing.
他还是个大呆瓜
He's also a huge dork.
姑娘们可喜欢了
Chicks dig that.
你说呢  我是抗拒这种诱惑呢
So what do you think? Should I fight this,
还是顺其自然
or run with it?
顺其自然吧  还是他...他
Run with it, right? Or did he... Was he...
他做了什么对不起你的事
What did he do that was so wrong to you?
什么都没做
Not a damn thing.
可谁说得准呢
But never say never.
挺不错的
It's nice.
什么
What is?
你和罗曼诺夫
You and Romanoff.
不  我们没...不是...
No, we haven't... That wasn't...
没事的
It's okay.
反正也没违规
Nobody's breaking any bylaws.
就是她一直都不怎么爱敞开内心
It's just she's not the most open person in the world.
可她跟你好像很放得开
But with you she seems very relaxed.
不是  娜塔莎她...就是喜欢调情
No. Natasha, she's just... She likes to flirt.
我见过  近距离的
I've seen her flirt, up close.
这次不是
This ain't that.
听我说
Look,
我大概是全世界
as maybe the world's
最会错过机会的人了  千万别错过
leading authority on waiting too long, don't.
你们都该找到对的人
You both deserve a win.
你说近距离是什么意思
What do you mean "up close"?
就是个戏法
But it's a trick.
不不  远不止那么简单
No, no, it's much more than that.
"无论谁  只要配得上  将拥有力量"
"Whosoever be he worthy shall haveth the power."
别闹了  就是个戏法
Whatever, man! It's a trick.
那来啊  随便试
Please, be my guest.
-试试  -真的吗
- Come on. - Really?
是啊
Yeah.
这回可好看了
This is gonna be beautiful.
克林特  你这周过得挺艰难
Clint, you've had a tough week.
举不起来[不举]我们也不笑你
We won't hold it against you if you can't get it up.
你知道我以前见过这个吧
You know I've seen this before, right?
还是不知道你怎么举的
I still don't know how you do it!
听到无言的嘲讽了吗
Smell the silent judgment?
快上  斯塔克  快请
Please, Stark, by all means.
好啊
Okay.
别人好心挑战  怎么能不应
Never one to shrink from an honest challenge.
加把劲
Get after it.
-就是物理学  -物理
- It's physics. - Physics.
如果我举起来  就统治阿斯加德了吗
Right, so, if I lift it, I then rule Asgard?
没错
Yes, of course.
我要恢复领主初夜权
I will be reinstituting prima nocta.
马上回来
I'll be right back.
你真用力了吗
Are you even pulling?
你跟我一伙的吗
Are you on my team?
我代表你  用力
Just represent. Pull.
好了  来
All right, let's go.
上吧  史蒂夫  别有压力
Go ahead, Steve. No pressure.
加油  队长
Come on, Cap.
没反应
Nothing.
黑寡妇呢
And, Widow?
不用了  我不好奇自己能不能举起来
No, no. That's not a question I need answered.
虽然我很尊敬你  但这锤子动了手脚
All deference to the Man Who Wouldn't Be King, but it's rigged.
可不他妈是吗
You bet your ass.
史蒂夫  他说脏话了
Steve, he said a bad language word.
你还四处宣扬吗
Did you tell everyone about that?
把手有识别功能  像是安保密码
The handle's imprinted, right? Like a security code.
"无论是谁  只要有托尔的指纹"
"Whosoever is carrying Thor's fingerprints"
锤子上的话是这个意思吧
is, I think, the literal translation.
是啊  这个说法很有意思
Yes. It's a very, very interesting theory.
我有个更简单的
I have a simpler one.
你们都配不上
You're all not worthy.
得了吧
Come on!
配得上
Worthy.
不
No.
你们怎么能配得上
How could you be worthy?
你们都是杀手
You're all killers.
-斯塔克  -贾维斯
- Stark. - Jarvis.
抱歉  我睡着了
I'm sorry, I was asleep.
或者做了个梦
Or I was a-dream.
重启军团操作系统  有战衣出故障了
Reboot Legionnaire OS. We got a buggy suit.
有吵人的声音
There was this terrible noise.
我被线缆...
And I was tangled in...
给...
in...
缠住了
strings.
我只能杀了那家伙  他还挺好的
I had to kill the other guy. He was a good guy.
你杀了谁
You killed someone?
我一开始也不想
Wouldn't have been my first call.
但在现实世界里  脏了手是难免的
But, down in the real world, we're faced with ugly choices.
谁派你来的
Who sent you?
我的设想是保护世界的战衣
I see a suit of armor around the world.
-奥创  -正是本人[肉体]
- Ultron. - In the flesh.
不对  还没肉体
Or, no, not yet.
这束缚着我的茧不算
Not this chrysalis.
但我准备好了
But I'm ready.
我在执行任务
I'm on mission.
-什么任务  -我们时代的和平
- What mission? - Peace in our time.
罗德
Rhodey!
抱歉
Sorry.
-别变绿  -不会的
- Don't turn green. - I won't.
走
Come on!
-斯塔克  -我们是来帮你们的
- Stark! - We are here to help.
稍等  稍等  我能搞定
One sec. One sec, I got this.
我们是来帮你们的
We are here to help.
请退后
Please back away.
托尔
Thor!
不安全...不安全...
...is unsafe. ...is unsafe...
-别这样  这还差不多  -不安全
- Come on! That's the one. - ...is unsafe.
队长
Hey, Cap!
闹得这么大
That was dramatic.
抱歉  我知道你是好心
I'm sorry, I know you mean well.
你只是没想周全
You just didn't think it through.
你想保护世界  又不想改变世界
You want to protect the world but you don't want it to change.
不允许人类进化
How is humanity saved
怎么可能拯救人类
if it's not allowed to evolve?
用这些吗  这种傀儡
With these? These puppets.
想和平只有一条路
There's only one path to peace.
消灭复仇者
The Avengers' extinction.
我曾被线束缚  现在我自由了
I had strings, but now I'm free.
我身上没有线了
There are no strings on me
看到没  我身上没有线了[出自《匹诺曹》]
But you can see there are no strings on me
我们的心血都没了
All our work is gone.
奥创给清光了  他用互联网逃走了
Ultron cleared out. He used the Internet as an escape hatch.
奥创
Ultron.
他什么都看过了  文件  监控
He's been in everything. Files, surveillance.
对我们的了解估计比彼此都深刻
Probably knows more about us than we know about each other.
他看了你的文件  进了互联网
He's in your files, he's in the Internet.
他要是想找更刺激的东西怎么办
What if he decides to access something a little more exciting?
核武器密码
Nuclear codes.
我们得打几个电话  前提是还能打
Look, we need to make some calls, assuming we still can.
核弹  他说要我们的命
Nukes? He said he wanted us dead.
他没说"要命"  说的是"消灭"
He didn't say "dead." He said "extinct."
他还说自己杀了谁
He also said he killed somebody.
这里没别人了啊
There wasn't anyone else in the building.
有的
Yes, there was.
什么
What?
太疯狂了
This is insane.
贾维斯是第一道防线
Jarvis was the first line of defense.
他要是还在  肯定会关闭奥创的
He would have shut Ultron down. It makes sense.
不  奥创本可以把贾维斯同化
No. Ultron could have assimilated Jarvis.
这不是策略  这是
This isn't strategy. This is
愤怒
rage.
怒火扩散开了
It's going around.
别这样  动口不动手  哥们
Come on, use your words, buddy.
跟你动口还不简单  斯塔克
I have more than enough words to describe you, Stark.
托尔  军团
Thor. The Legionnaire.
跟了一百英里就不见了  但是向北去了
Trail went cold about 100 miles out, but it's headed north.
它拿了权杖
And it has the scepter.
又得麻烦大伙拿回来了
Now we have to retrieve it, again.
灯神已经飞出了神灯
Genie's out of that bottle.
奥创是当务之急
Clear and present is Ultron.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你自己编写的程序
You built this program.
为什么要杀我们
Why is it trying to kill us?
你觉得好笑吗
You think this is funny?
不
No.
应该不好笑吧
It's probably not, right?
真是糟糕  真是...
This is very terrible. Is it so...
真是...  真是糟糕
Is it so... It is. It's so terrible.
如果不是你
This could have been avoided
乱摆弄自己不懂的东西  就不会到这步
if you hadn't played with something you don't understand.
不  对不起  对不起  是很好笑
No. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. It is funny.
你不懂我们为什么需要这个真是好笑
It's a hoot that you don't get why we need this.
托尼  现在说这个不好吧
Tony, maybe this might not be the time.
真的吗  就这样
Really? That's it?
一有人发火  你就跑过来当和事佬
You just roll over, show your belly every time somebody snarls?
我造了个杀人机器人时才这样
Only when I've created a murder bot.
没有  差得远呢  连界面都差得远呢吧
We didn't. We weren't even close. Were we close to an interface?
至少你做对了点什么  就在这
Well, you did something right. And you did it right here.
复仇者联盟不应该像神盾局一样
The Avengers were supposed to be different than S.H.I.E.L.D.
还有人记得我扛着核弹穿过虫洞吗
Anybody remember when I carried a nuke through a wormhole?
-没想起来  -拯救了纽约
- No, it's never come up. - Saved New York?
-没听说过  -还记得吗
- Never heard that. - Recall that?
一支外星人大军穿过虫洞入侵地球
A hostile alien army came charging through a hole in space.
我们就在虫洞正下面
We're standing 300 feet below it.
我们是复仇者联盟
We're the Avengers.
我们可以天天抓军火商玩
We can bust arms dealers all the livelong day,
但上面那个虫洞...
but that up there, that's...
那种残局
That's the endgame.
那种敌人你们怎么打败
How were you guys planning on beating that?
齐心协力
Together.
我们会输的
We'll lose.
那就一起输
Then we'll do that together, too.
托尔说得对  奥创在挑战我们
Thor's right. Ultron's calling us out.
我要在他准备好之前找到他
And I'd like to find him before he's ready for us.
世界这么大  先缩小下范围
The world's a big place. Let's start making it smaller.
说吧  如果你浪费了我们的时间...
Talk, and if you are wasting our time...
你们知道这教堂是城市的正中心吗
Did you know this church is in the exact center of the city?
先人们决定建在这
The elders decreed it so
这样大家能离上帝一样近
that everyone could be equally close to God.
我喜欢
I like that.
信仰的几何学
The geometry of belief.
你在好奇为什么看不透我的意识
You're wondering why you can't look inside my head.
有时候是很难
Sometimes it's hard.
但不管什么人  早晚会现形的
But sooner or later, every man shows himself.
可不是嘛
I'm sure they do.
可你不止需要一个"人"
But you needed something more than a man.
所以你才让斯塔克拿走权杖
That's why you let Stark take the scepter.
我没想到
I didn't expect,
但我看到了斯塔克的恐惧
but I saw Stark's fear.
知道他会被恐惧控制
I knew it would control him.
最终毁灭自己
Make him self-destruct.
恐惧的事物都是自己创造的
Everyone creates the thing they dread.
和平人士创造了战争机器
Men of peace create engines of war.
入侵者创造了复仇者
Invaders create Avengers.
人类创造了
People create
更小的人
smaller people?
"孩子"  忘了怎么说了
"Children." I lost the word, there.
孩子
Children
用来取代他们
designed to supplant them,
帮助他们消亡
to help them end.
你来是为这个吗  让复仇者消亡
Is that why you've come, to end the Avengers?
我是来拯救世界的
I've come to save the world.
不过你也没说错
But also... Yeah.
我们马上走
We'll move out right away.
这只是个开始
This is a start,
想要开工  还需要点别的
but there's something we need to begin the real work.
-这些都是...  -我
- All of these are... - Me.
我有样东西复仇者永远不会有  和谐
I have what the Avengers never will. Harmony.
他们就是盘散沙
They're discordant. Disconnected.
斯塔克已经让他们之间有了敌意
Stark's already got them turning on each other.
等你进入了他们的意识
And when you get inside the rest of their heads...
别人都没打算杀他们
Everyone's plan is not to kill them.
让他们成为殉道者吗
And make them martyrs?
得有耐心
You need patience.
得看大局[照片]
Need to see the big picture.
我看不到大局  我只有张小照片
I don't see the big picture. I have a little picture.
我经常拿出来看
I take it out and look at it,
每天都是
every day.
你们的父母在轰炸中丧生  我看了档案
You lost your parents in the bombings. I've seen the records.
档案又不是照片
The records are not the picture.
皮特
Pietro.
不  说吧
No, please.
我们才十岁  一家四口吃着晚饭
We were 10 years old. Having dinner, the four of us.
第一枚炸弹击中了下面两层楼
When the first shell hits, two floors below,
楼板破了个洞
it makes a hole in the floor.
好大的洞
It's big.
爸妈掉了下去
Our parents go in
整栋楼都开始倒塌
and the whole building starts coming apart.
我抓住她
I grab her,
躲到了床下  然后是第二枚
roll under the bed, and the second shell hits.
可是没有爆炸
But it doesn't go off.
它就
It just
在那静静待着
sits there in the rubble.
离我们只有三英尺
Three feet from our faces.
炸弹旁边印着一个词
And on the side of the shell is painted one word.
"斯塔克"
"Stark."
我们被困在那两天
We were trapped for two days.
每次有人想救我们
Every effort to save us,
哪怕只挪了一块碎砖
every shift in the bricks,
我都想  "会引爆炸弹吧"
I think, "this will set it off."
我们等托尼·斯塔克杀我们  等了两天
We wait for two days for Tony Stark to kill us.
我知道他们什么样
I know what they are.
我还好奇  斯托克的实验怎么就你们两个幸存者
I wondered why only you two survived Strucker's experiments.
现在明白了
Now I don't.
我们会讨回正义
We will make it right.
我们是可以伤到他们
You and I can hurt them.
但你可以从内部
But you will tear them apart
把他们瓦解
from the inside.
全世界都有他的足迹
He's all over the globe.
机器人实验室  武器库  喷气动力实验室
Robotics labs, weapons facilities, jet propulsion labs.
都说有金属人  有时候好多个  过去清空了他们那里
Reports of a metal man, or men, coming in and emptying the place.
伤亡呢
Fatalities?
不交火的话没有
Only when engaged.
他们都变得神情恍惚
Mostly guys left in a fugue state
说着什么回忆  最深处的恐惧
going on about old memories, worst fears,
还有东西"快到看不见"
and "something too fast to see."
马克西莫夫兄妹
Maximoffs.
难怪他会找他们  他们都认识同一个人
That makes sense he'd go to them. They have someone in common.
已经不在了
Not anymore.
和平
不行  我向你汇报
That's a negative. I answer to you.
遵命
Yes, ma'am.
巴顿  好像有线索了
Barton. Might have something.
得挂了
I gotta go.
谁啊
Who was that?
女朋友
Girlfriend.
这是什么
What's this?
信息  奥创杀了斯托克
A message. Ultron killed Strucker.
还涂了个鸦  专为我们呢
And he did a Banksy at the crime scene, just for us.
这是烟幕弹
This is a smoke screen.
能直说为什么还要这样做
Why send a message when you've just given a speech?
斯托克有情报  奥创不想让我们知道
Strucker knew something that Ultron wanted us to miss.
是啊  他应该...没错
Yeah, I bet he... Yeah.
有关斯托克的文件都被删除了
Everything we had on Strucker's been erased.
并没有
Not everything.
已知同伙
Known associates.
斯托克男爵有好多朋友啊
Baron Strucker had a lot of friends.
这群人都好可怕
Well, these people are all horrible.
等等  我认识他
Wait. I know that guy.
他一直在非洲沿岸做生意
From back in the day. He operates off the African coast.
黑市军火商
Black market arms.
交集是难免的  同行免不了见面
There are conventions. All right? You meet people.
我没卖过他东西
I didn't sell him anything.
他说了要找什么新的  改变世界的东西
He was talking about finding something new, a game-changer.
搞得跟以色列王似的
It was all very Ahab.
这是什么
This?
是个纹身  之前好像没有
It's a tattoo, I don't think he had it.
那些是纹身  这是烙印
Those are tattoos, this is a brand.
是非洲土著语  意思是贼
Yeah. It's a word in an African dialect meaning "thief."
而且很有侮辱性
In a much less friendly way.
-什么土著语  -瓦坎纳达
- What dialect? - Wakanada.
瓦坎达
Wakanda.
如果他从瓦坎达带了什么东西出来...
If this guy got out of Wakanda with some of their trade goods...
你父亲不是都拿走了吗
I thought your father said he got the last of it.
没明白  从瓦坎达拿走了什么
I don't follow. What comes out of Wakanda?
世界上最坚固的金属
The strongest metal on Earth.
他现在在哪
Where is this guy now?
废船厂
非洲海岸
别跟我说你被手下骗了
Don't tell me your men swindled you.
我给了你六枚
I sent you six short-range
短程热感导弹  你给我一船废铁
heat-seekers and got a boat full of rusted parts.
你得补偿我
Now, you will make it right,
不然再送你枚灰在天上的导弹
or the next missile I send you will come very much faster.
好了  部长  说到哪了
Now, minister, where were we?
能力增强者
Yeah. The Enhanced.
斯托克的好学生
Strucker's prize pupils.
要吃糖吗
Do you want a candy?
斯托克死了真遗憾
I was sorry to hear about Strucker.
不过他也知道自己想把世界变成什么样
But then, he knew what kind of world he was helping create.
人类啊  没什么前途的
Human life. Not a growth market.
你不知道吗
You didn't know?
这是你们第一次威胁别人吗
Is this your first time intimidating someone?
恐怕我没那么怕
I'm afraid I'm not that afraid.
人人都有恐惧的东西
Everybody is afraid of something.
墨鱼
Cuttlefish.
深海动物
Deep sea fish.
会用光  迷幻的光
They make lights, disco lights...
迷惑猎物  然后...
...to hypnotize their prey, and then...
我看了纪录片  可恐怖了
I saw a documentary. It was terrifying.
如果你要鼓捣我的意识
So if you're going to fiddle with my brain
让我看见大墨鱼
and make me see a giant cuttlefish,
我就知道你不是来做生意的
then I know you don't do business.
我也知道你说了不算
And I know you're not in charge.
我只跟
And I only deal
说了算的人打交道
with the man in charge.
说了算的不是人
There is no man in charge.
来谈生意吧
Let's talk business.
《马太福音》16:18
我在这块磐石上  建立我的教会
Upon this rock, I will build my church.
振金
Vibranium.
告诉你
You know,
这东西代价可不小
it came at great personal cost.
值几十亿
It's worth billions.
你也是了
Now so are you.
传到你的假账户里了
It's all under your dummy holdings.
金融真是奇怪
Finance is so weird.
但我总是说
But I always say,
"要让朋友敌人一起富
"Keep your friends rich and your enemies rich
电汇完成
"是敌是友自然分清楚"
"And wait to find out which is which."
斯塔克
Stark.
什么
What?
托尼·斯塔克说过这个
Tony Stark used to say that.
对我说的
To me.
你是他手下
You're one of his.
什么  我不是...
What? I'm not...
我不是
I'm not.
你以为我是斯塔克的傀儡吗
You think I'm one of Stark's puppets?
全听他吩咐
His hollow men?
看看我  我长得像钢铁侠吗
I mean, look at me. Do I look like Iron Man?
斯塔克算什么
Stark is nothing!
真是抱歉  我...
I'm sorry. I'm...
一会就没事了  真是抱歉
I'm sure that's gonna be okay. I'm sorry.
我就是不明白
It's just that I don't understand.
别拿我跟斯塔克比
Don't compare me with Stark!
我在意这个
It's a thing with me.
斯塔克...  就是顽疾
Stark is... He's a sickness!
小子
Junior.
你真要把老爹的心伤得稀碎
You're gonna break your old man's heart.
如果有必要的话
If I have to.
谁也不用打碎东西
Nobody has to break anything.
没做过鸡蛋饼吧
Clearly you've never made an omelet.
这句都到我嘴边了
He beat me by one second.
还真是幽默
Yes. He's funny.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark.
感觉亲切吗
It's what? Comfortable?
就像以前一样
Like old times?
我以前可没这样过
This was never my life.
你们俩没必要蹚这浑水
You two can still walk away from this.
不  现在有必要
No, we will.
我知道你们受过苦
I know you've suffered.
美国队长
Captain America.
上帝的正义之子
God's righteous man.
假装自己不是战争机器
Pretending you could live without a war.
我要是人类的话早吐了
I can't physically throw up in my mouth, but...
你要是相信和平  就不要打破它
If you believe in peace, then let us keep it.
你混淆了"和平"与"安宁"的概念
I think you're confusing "peace" with "quiet."
你要振金做什么
What's the vibranium for?
你终于开口问了
I'm glad you asked that,
让我给你们解释下我邪恶的计划
because I wanted to take this time to explain my evil plan.
-开火  -朝谁
- Shoot them. - Which ones?
所有人
All of them!
上上上
Move! Move! Move!
待着吧  孩子
Stay down, kid.
该玩玩他们的意识了
It's time for some mind games.
各位  需要我变绿吗
Guys? Is this a code green?
托尔  什么情况
Thor, status.
那小姑娘想扰乱我的心智
The girl tried to warp my mind.
小心了  凡人恐怕挡不住她的意识控制
Take special care. I doubt a human could keep her at bay.
幸好  我是神
Fortunately, I am mighty.
这进展得太顺利了
This is going very well.
精神控制什么的我早就尝过了
I've done the whole mind control thing.
真不感兴趣
Not a fan.
别让我逮着你
Yeah, you better run.
活着的  得行动了
Who's ever standing, we got to move!
各位
Guys?
再来
Again.
她们会撑不住的
You'll break them.
撑不下来的是活该
Only the breakable ones.
而你坚若磐石
You're made of marble.
毕业典礼后我们再庆祝
We'll celebrate after the graduation ceremony.
如果我失败了呢
What if I fail?
你从不失败
You never fail.
准备好跟我共舞了吗
Are you ready for our dance?
是他吗
Is it him?
是奥丁的长子吗
Is that the first son of Odin?
海姆达尔  你的眼睛
Heimdall, your eyes.
它们看清了一切
They see everything.
看到你带领我们走向冥府
They see you leading us to Hel.
醒醒
Wake up!
战争结束了  史蒂夫
The war is over, Steve.
我们可以回家了
We can go home.
想想看
Imagine it.
我还能拯救你
I can still save you!
我们都死了  你看不到吗
We're all dead! Can you not see?
你是毁灭者  奥丁森
You're a destroyer, Odinson.
看看你的神力干了什么
See where your power leads.
太大意了
Sloppy.
你是故意失败吗
Pretending to fail.
必须通过毕业典礼
The ceremony is necessary
你才能立足在世界上
for you to take your place in the world.
我没有地方可以立足
I have no place in the world.
没错
Exactly.
-我该怎么办  -好疼
- What can I do? - It hurts.
我去杀了他
I'm going to kill him.
-马上回来  -不
- I'll be right back. - No.
我没事
I'm all right.
我要...我要完成计划
I want... I want to finish the plan.
搞定那个大家伙
I want the big one.
振金被运走了哦
The vibranium is getting away.
你哪也别想去
And you're not going anywhere.
不需要  我已经无处不在了
Of course not. I'm already there.
你会明白的
You'll catch on.
但首先你得搞定班纳博士
But first, you might need to catch Dr. Banner.
搜索新闻视频  关键词"绿巨人"
News or footage. Keyword, "Hulk."
娜塔莎  你得过来唱摇篮曲了
Natasha, I could really use a lullaby.
不行  这一阵她是不行了
That's not gonna happen. Not for a while.
大伙都倒下了
The whole team is down.
现在没人能支援你了
You got no backup here.
那我呼叫维罗妮卡
I'm calling in Veronica.
我们需要支援
We need backup!
离开这  快走
Go! Keep moving!
好了  所有人退后
All right, everybody, stand down!
听我一句行吗
Will you listen to me?
那个小女巫搞乱了你的头脑
That little witch is messing with your mind.
你比她更强  也更聪明
You're stronger than her. You're smarter than her.
你可是布鲁斯·班纳啊
You're Bruce Banner.
我错了  我错了  不能提小班纳
Right, right, right, don't mention puny Banner.
好吧
Okay!
背后偷袭
In the back?
太阴险了  班纳
Dick move, Banner.
维罗妮卡  搭把手
Veronica, give me a hand.
听话  听话  快睡觉
Go to sleep, go to sleep, go to sleep.
好吧  伙计  先把你弄出城
Okay, pal, we're gonna get you out of town.
别去那边  别去那边
Not that way, not that way.
拜托  布鲁斯  配合一下
Come on, Bruce! You gotta work with me.
所有人都出去
Everybody, out!
下去了
Going down?
对不起
I'm sorry.
损伤报告
Damage report?
真直白  再运点零件来
That's comprehensive. Show me something.
搜索生命迹象
无人员在内
安全
买下这栋楼最快得多久
How quickly can we buy this building?
-行动  行动  行动  -上上上
- Move! Move! Move! - Go, go, go!
去侧翼  去侧翼
Flank him, flank him!
电视台可喜欢报道你们了呢
The news is loving you guys.
但大家都不喜欢
Nobody else is.
警方还没发布班纳的逮捕令
There's been no official call for Banner's arrest
但消息已经传开了
but it's in the air.
斯塔克救援基金呢
The Stark Relief Foundation?
已经在现场了
Already on the scene.
团队怎么样
How's the team?
大家都...
Everyone's...
我们受了重创  不过会好的
We took a hit. We'll shake it off.
现在最好一直潜伏  别再回来
Well, for now, I'd stay in stealth mode and stay away from here.
就是逃走藏起来
So, run and hide?
找不到奥创
Until we can find Ultron,
我也没什么好办法
I don't have a lot else to offer.
我们也没有
Neither do we.
要换班吗
Hey, you wanna switch out?
我没事
No, I'm good.
你要是想睡觉  最好趁现在
If you wanna get some kip, now's a good time
还有几个小时才到呢
because we're still a few hours out.
到哪
Few hours from where?
安全屋
A safe house.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
安全屋
Safe house.
但愿吧
Let's hope.
亲爱的
Honey?
我到家了
I'm home.
你好
Hi.
还有朋友
Company.
抱歉没提前打电话
Sorry, didn't call ahead.
他绝对是个什么特工
This is an agent of some kind.
各位  这是劳拉
Gentlemen, this is Laura.
你们我全都知道
I know all of your names.
来了
Incoming.
-爸爸  -宝贝们
- Dad! - Hi, sweetheart!
小伙子
Hey, buddy.
你们好吗
How are you guys doing?
-这些是小特工  -看你的脸
- These are smaller agents. - Look at your face!
我的天
Oh, my goodness.
小娜阿姨来了吗
Did you bring Auntie Nat?
来抱一个看来没来
Why don't you hug her and find out?
抱歉打扰你们了
Sorry for barging in on you.
是啊  本来想提前打电话的
Yeah, we would have called ahead,
但我们根本不知道你们的存在
but we were busy having no idea that you existed.
我加入神盾局的时候弗瑞帮我安排的
Yeah, well, Fury helped me set this up when I joined.
这里没有进神盾局的档案
He kept it off S.H.I.E.L.D.'s files.
以后最好也不要
I'd like to keep it that way.
这地方挺适合暂时藏身的
I figure it's a good place to lay low.
亲爱的
Honey.
我好想你
I missed you.
小娜塔莎怎么样
How's little Natasha?
她是...
She's...
内特尼尔[男名]
Nathaniel.
叛徒
Traitor.
托尔
Thor?
我在梦里看到了什么
I saw something in that dream.
我需要找答案  这里找不到
I need answers. I won't find them here.
我们可以回家了
We can go home.
你都是瞎担心
See? You worried for nothing.
我是感觉不出来  你呢
Can't even feel the difference, can you?
他们要是住这的话
If they're sleeping here,
有的人就得挤一挤了
some of them are gonna have to double up.
他们肯定不愿意
Yeah, that's not gonna sell.
小娜和班纳博士怎么回事
What about Nat and Dr. Banner?
她俩有多久了
How long has that been going on?
什么多久
Has what?
你真可爱
You are so cute.
小娜和班纳
Nat and Banner?
等你长大了再跟你解释
I'll explain when you're older,
鹰眼
Hawkeye.
好吧
Well, okay.
情况不妙吧
It's bad, right?
小娜好像很受伤
Nat seems really shaken.
奥创有两个盟友
Ultron has these allies.
两个孩子  都是小流氓
These kids. They're punks, really.
他们拿了根特别大的棍子
But they carry a big, damn stick.
小娜挨了挺重的一下
And Nat took a serious hit.
得有人教训教训他们
Someone's gonna have to teach them some manners.
那个人就是你吗
That someone being you.
你当复仇者我非常支持
You know I totally support your Avenging.
我无比自豪
I couldn't be prouder.
但我看到他们...
But I see those guys...
神一样的...
Those gods...
你觉得他们不需要我
You don't think they need me.
我觉得他们需要  这样更可怕
I think they do, which is a lot scarier.
他们问题真是多啊
They're a mess.
是啊
Yeah.
那也是我的问题
I guess they're my mess.
你得确保
You need to be sure
团队能合作下去
that this team is really a team,
能时刻支持你
and that they have your back.
我们的日子也要变了
Things are changing for us.
再过几个月
In a few months' time,
孩子就要比大人多了
you and me are gonna be outnumbered.
我得...
I need...
一定要确保
Just be sure.
遵命
Yes, ma'am.
我能感觉到不一样
I can feel the difference.
尤金基因实验室
韩国  首尔
敢出声  你的员工都得死
Scream, and your entire staff dies.
我本可以杀了你  海伦  刚见面那晚
I could've killed you, Helen, the night we met.
但我没有
I didn't.
是要我谢你吗
Do you expect a thank-you note?
我要你知道为什么
I expect you to know why.
再生摇篮
The Cradle.
这就是未来  托尼
This is the next thing, Tony.
这就是未来的我
This is the next me.
再生摇篮能生成组织
The Regeneration Cradle prints tissue.
可造不出活的躯体
It can't build a living body.
可以  你可以
It can. You can.
你只是缺少材料
You lack the materials.
你很厉害  海伦
You're a brilliant woman, Helen.
但大家都有进步的空间
But we all have room to improve.
我不知道你在等着
I didn't realize you were waiting.
我想跟你一起洗来着
I would've joined you,
但是好像时机不太对
but it didn't seem like the right time.
热水被他们用光了
They used up all the hot water.
真该跟你一起洗
I should've joined you.
错过了机会
Missed our window.
是吗
Did we?
世界看到了绿巨人
The world just saw the Hulk.
第一次见到了真正的绿巨人
The real Hulk, for the first time.
你知道我得离开
You know I have to leave.
你是觉得我应该留下吗
You assume that I have to stay?
我做了个梦
I had this dream.
做梦的时候觉得挺正常
The kind that seems normal at the time,
但等醒了...
but when you wake...
你梦见什么了
What did you dream?
我是复仇者
That I was an Avenger.
不只是他们一手打造的刺客
That I was anything more than the assassin they made me.
你对自己太狠[硬]了
I think you're being hard on yourself.
这不是你该干的吗
Here I was hoping that was your job.
你干什么
What are you doing?
顺其自然
I'm running with it.
和你一起
With you.
如果你打算走
If running is the plan,
想去哪去哪
as far as you want.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
我希望你明白...
I want you to understand that...
娜塔莎
Natasha,
我能去哪
where can I go?
我到哪不是个祸害
Where in the world am I not a threat?
-在我这不是  -你确定吗
- You're not a threat to me. - Are you sure?
哪怕我没...
Even if I didn't just...
跟着我没有未来的
There's no future with me.
我不能...
I can't ever...
我不可能这样
I can't have this.
有孩子
Kids.
你自己想想  我是真的不能
Do the math. I physically can't.
我也不能
Neither can I.
我受训的那个红屋子里...
In the Red Room where I was trained...
我长大的地方
where I was raised,
有个毕业典礼
they have a graduation ceremony.
就是做绝育
They sterilize you.
效果很好
It's efficient.
少了件操心的事
One less thing to worry about.
唯一一件可能比任务还重要的事
The one thing that might matter more than a mission.
一切都简单多了
Makes everything easier.
哪怕是杀人
Even killing.
你还以为队伍里就你一个怪物吗
You still think you're the only monster on the team?
我们一起隐居吗
So, we disappear?
托尔没说他去哪找答案了吗
Thor didn't say where he was going for answers?
我的队员也不总跟我畅所欲言的
Sometimes my teammates don't tell me things.
我还希望托尔能对我敞开胸襟呢
I was kind of hoping Thor would be the exception.
给他点时间
Yeah, give him time.
我们不知道马克西莫夫给他看了什么
We don't know what the Maximoff kid showed him.
"地球上最强大的英雄组合"
"Earth's mightiest heroes."
棉花糖一样被拆散了
Pulled us apart like cotton candy.
你好像没什么大碍嘛
Seems like you walked away all right.
有问题吗
Is that a problem?
没有黑暗面的人不值得信任
I don't trust a guy without a dark side.
就算我老古董吧
Call me old-fashioned.
那只是你还没见过
Well, let's just say you haven't seen it yet.
你知道奥创想分裂我们吧
You know Ultron is trying to tear us apart, right?
你肯定知道
Well, I guess you'd know.
会不会告诉我们就不一定了
Whether you'd tell us is a bit of a question.
班纳和我在搞科研
Banner and I were doing research.
-会对团队有影响  -是会解散团队吧
- That would affect the team. - That would end the team!
那不正是目的吗
Isn't that the mission?
不是我们战斗的理由吗
Isn't that the "why we fight"?
为了结束战斗  为了回家
So we can end the fight. So we get to go home!
每次有人想在战争开打前取胜
Every time someone tries to win a war before it starts,
都会牺牲无辜的人  每次都是
innocent people die. Every time.
真抱歉
I'm sorry.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark...
克林特说你不会介意的
Clint said you wouldn't mind,
我家的拖拉机启动不了了
but our tractor doesn't seem to want to start at all.
-你能不能去...  -没问题  我去看看
- I thought maybe you might... - Yeah, I'll give her a kick.
别偷我劈的柴
Don't take from my pile.
好啊亲爱的
Hello, Dear.
来给我讲讲
Tell me everything.
哪里不舒服
What ails you?
行行好
Do me a favor.
别把它弄活了
Try not to bring it to life.
巴顿夫人还真是狡猾
Why, Ms. Barton, you little minx.
我明白了  希尔给你打电话了
I get it. Maria Hill called you, right?
她有不给你打工的时候吗
Was she ever not working for you?
人工智能
Artificial intelligence.
你都没犹豫一下
You never even hesitated.
今天真的很漫长
Look, it's been a really long day,
有尤金·奥尼尔的小说[同名]那么长
like Eugene O'Neill long,
来直接说你能解决什么问题
so how's about we skip to the part where you're useful.
看着我的眼睛  告诉我你会关闭奥创
Look me in the eye and tell me you're going to shut him down.
你又不是我的局长
You're not the director of me.
我谁的局长都不是
I'm not the director of anybody.
我就是个老头子
I'm just an old man
刚好很关心你
who cares very much about you.
我是害死复仇者联盟的人
And I'm the man who killed the Avengers.
我看到了
I saw it.
我没告诉大伙  没法说
I didn't tell the team. How could I?
我看到他们都死了  尼克  我感觉到了
I saw them all dead, Nick. I felt it.
世界也终结了
The whole world, too.
因为我
Because of me.
我没准备好
I wasn't ready.
我没尽力
I didn't do all I could.
这是马克西莫夫的把戏  斯塔克
Maximoff girl, she's working you, Stark.
利用你的恐惧
Playing on your fear.
不是把戏  我真看到了
I wasn't tricked, I was shown.
不是噩梦  是我留给后人的
Wasn't a nightmare, it was my legacy.
我带着大家走向了死亡
The end of the path I started us on.
你是发明过不少厉害的玩意  托尼
You come up with some pretty impressive inventions, Tony.
可战争不是
War isn't one of them.
我看到朋友死去
I watched my friends die.
你觉得这够惨了吗
You'd think that'd be as bad as it gets, right?
还不够
Nope.
那还不是最坏的
It wasn't the worst part.
最坏的是
The worst part
只有你没死
is that you didn't.
今晚见了
I'll see you tonight.
皇家霍罗威大学
伦敦
造型不错
I like the look.
不过想不惹人注意还差点
If you're going for inconspicuous, though, near miss.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
有人需要真好
It's nice to be needed.
很危险
It's dangerous.
不危险我才失望呢
I'd be disappointed if it wasn't.
奥创把你们赶走  好给自己争取时间
Ultron took you folks out of play to buy himself time.
我的线人都说他在打造什么
My contacts all say he's building something.
他弄了那么多振金
The amount of vibranium he made off with,
应该不止一件
I don't think it's just one thing.
那奥创呢
What about Ultron himself?
他好追踪  哪都有他
He's easy to track. He's everywhere.
他比母猪还高产
The guy is multiplying faster than a Catholic rabbit.
可还是看不透
It still doesn't help us
他究竟在计划什么
get an angle on any of his plans, though.
还想找核弹密码吗
Is he still going after launch codes?
是啊
Yes, he is.
可一直没什么进展
But he's not making any headway.
我高中玩大冒险就把五角大楼的防火墙破了
I cracked the Pentagon's firewall in high school on a dare.
我联系了"链结"的朋友
Well, I contacted our friends at the Nexus about that.
链结
Nexus?
奥斯陆的互联网中心
It's the world internet hub in Oslo.
所有联网数据都要经过那里
Every byte of data flows through there.
全球最快的连接速度
Fastest access on Earth.
他们怎么说
So, what did they say?
他认准了核弹
He's fixated on the missiles.
但密码一直在改
But the codes are constantly being changed.
谁在改
By whom?
未知势力
Parties unknown.
我们有盟友吗
Do we have an ally?
奥创有个对手  这可不一样
Ultron's got an enemy. That's not the same thing.
我还是特别想知道幕后是谁
Still, I'd pay folding money to know who it is.
我得去趟奥斯陆
I might need to visit Oslo.
寻找未知势力
Find our unknown.
跟你重聚很开心  老大
Well, this is good times, boss,
但我本希望你这次来
but I was kind of hoping when I saw you,
你能多带点什么来
you'd have more than that.
我还有你们啊
I do. I have you.
过去遍地都是我的眼线  哪都不放过
Back in the day, I had eyes everywhere. Ears, everywhere else.
你们手里什么高科技都有
You kids had all the tech you could dream up.
可是现在  大伙回到了地球上
Here we all are, back on Earth,
只能靠自己的智慧和意志拯救世界
with nothing but our wit and our will to save the world.
奥创说阻止他实现目的的
Ultron says the Avengers are the only thing
就只有复仇者联盟了
between him and his mission.
不管他承不承认
And whether or not he admits it,
他的任务都是毁灭全球
his mission is global destruction.
这一切  都将入土
All this, laid in a grave.
站出来吧
So stand.
战胜那个金属王八蛋
Outwit the platinum bastard.
史蒂夫不喜欢你这么说
Steve doesn't like that kind of talk.
告诉你  罗曼诺夫
You know what, Romanoff?
他想要什么
So, what does he want?
变得更好
To become better.
比我们都好
Better than us.
他一直在造身体
He keeps building bodies.
人的身体
Person bodies.
人类的性能太差
The human form is inefficient.
生物角度上讲  我们被被淘汰了
Biologically speaking, we're outmoded.
可他还总要回来找我们
But he keeps coming back to it.
你们两个设定要他保护人类时
When you two programmed him to protect the human race,
真是失败得一塌糊涂
you amazingly failed.
他们不需要保护
They don't need to be protected.
需要进化
They need to evolve.
奥创要进化
Ultron's going to evolve.
怎么进化
How?
有人联系过海伦·赵吗
Has anyone been in contact with Helen Cho?
真美
It's beautiful.
振金原子不仅能跟组织共存
The vibranium atoms aren't just compatible with the tissue cells,
还结合了起来
they're binding them.
神盾局居然从没想过...
And S.H.I.E.L.D. Never even thought to...
地球上功能最多的材料
The most versatile substance on the planet,
居然用它做飞盘
and they used it to make a Frisbee.
人类就是这样
Typical of humans.
研究一点就浅尝辄止
They scratch the surface and never think
不想深入
to look within.
我带娜塔莎和克林特
I'll take Natasha and Clint.
好  只是侦查  我先去链接
All right. Strictly recon. I'll hit the Nexus.
办完就找你们
I'll join you as soon as I can.
如果奥创真在造躯体
If Ultron's really building a body...
他就比我们谁都强了
He'll be more powerful than any of us.
也许比我们一起都强
Maybe all of us.
机器人设计的机器人
An android designed by a robot.
放在过去  我就是科学创造的
You know, I really miss the days
最奇怪的发明  想想真是怀念
when the weirdest thing science ever created was me.
我把班纳送到复仇者塔楼那
I'll drop Banner off at the tower.
希尔女士可以借我吗
You mind if I borrow Ms. Hill?
归你了  早就归你了
She's all yours. Apparently.
你准备干什么
What are you gonna do?
不知道  但愿能弄点戏剧性的
I don't know. Something dramatic, I hope.
我一回来就重铺一遍日光浴室的地板
I'm gonna finish reflooring that sunroom as soon as I get back.
好啊  然后再在房子里找个能祸害的地方
Yeah, then you'll find another part of the house to tear apart.
不
No.
那是最后一项了
It's the last project.
我保证
I promise.
就是这了
So, this is it.
真视之水
The Water of Sight.
每个国度都有倒影
In every realm, there's a reflection.
如果水中神灵肯接纳我
If the water's spirits accept me,
我就可以回到梦里
I can return to my dream
找到我错过了什么
and find what I missed.
传说进去的人都没什么好结局
Men who enter that water, the legends don't end well.
比奥创还快的黑客吗
A hacker who's faster than Ultron?
在哪都有可能
He could be anywhere,
"链接"互联网中心
这不是一切的中心吗
and as this is the center of everything,
挪威  奥斯陆
我只不过是
I'm just a guy looking for
想在最广的海洋里捞出一根针
a needle in the world's biggest haystack.
怎么捞
How do you find it?
很简单  用磁铁
It's pretty simple. You bring a magnet.
我在破解核武器密码
I'm decrypting nuclear codes
你不允许我
and you don't want me to.
来抓我呀
Come and get me.
醒醒
Wake up!
托尔
Thor!
灭绝
Extinction.
细胞过几小时才能凝聚
Cellular cohesion will take a few hours,
不过可以开始传输意识了
but we can initiate the consciousness stream.
上传你大脑的程序
We're uploading your cerebral matrix
开始
now.
我能感知他
I can read him.
他在做梦
He's dreaming.
应该不会是梦
I wouldn't call it dreams.
是奥创的基础意识
It's Ultron's base consciousness.
都是信息噪音  很快...
Informational noise. Soon...
多快
How soon?
不是催你
I'm not being pushy.
还在制造大脑组织
We're imprinting a physical brain.
没有更快的方法
There are no shortcuts.
哪怕有魔法宝石...
Even if your magic gem...
你怎么敢
How could you?
我怎么什么
How could I what?
你说我们会消灭复仇者
You said we would destroy the Avengers,
让世界更美好
make a better world.
是会更美好
It will be better.
等人类都死了吗
When everyone is dead?
那不是...
That is not...
我会给人类充足的机会进化的
The human race will have every opportunity to improve.
进化不了呢
And if they don't?
问问诺亚
Ask Noah.
你是个疯子
You are a madman.
恐龙灭绝之前  地球上就有过
There were more than a dozen extinction-level events
不少次导致种族灭绝的灾难
before even the dinosaurs got theirs.
地球一稳定
When the Earth starts to settle,
上帝就扔块石头
God throws a stone at it.
相信我  他在准备着了
And, believe me, he's winding up.
我们必须进化
We have to evolve.
弱者
There's no room
不可以存活
for the weak.
谁来决定谁是弱者
And who decides who's weak?
生命
Life.
都是生命决定的
Life always decides.
有人来了
There's incoming.
昆式战斗机  得走了
The Quinjet. We have to move.
没问题
That's not a problem.
等等  各位
Wait, guys!
他们会理解的
They'll understand.
等他们看到了  就会理解的
When they see, they'll understand.
我还需要点时间
I just need a little more time.
两分钟  保持联络
Two minutes. Stay close.
赵博士
Dr. Cho!
他在把自己上传到躯体里
He's uploading himself into the body.
哪
Where?
真正强大的东西在摇篮里
The real power is inside the Cradle.
宝石
The gem,
是没法驾驭的
its power is uncontainable.
不能炸掉了事
You can't just blow it up.
得把摇篮带给斯塔克
You have to get the Cradle to Stark.
我得先找到摇篮
First, I have to find it.
去吧
Go.
你们收到了吗
Did you guys copy that?
收到
We did.
有架私人飞机在对岸起飞
I got a private jet taking off across town.
没有乘客
No manifest.
可能是他
That could be him.
那里  实验室的卡车
There. It's a truck from the lab.
就在你上面  队长
Right above you, Cap.
引桥上
On the loop by the bridge.
是他们
It's them.
三个守着摇篮  车厢里一个
You got three with the Cradle, one in the cab.
我可以干掉司机
I could take out the driver.
不行  卡车毁了
Negative. That truck crashes,
宝石会毁掉一座城的
the gem could level the city.
得把奥创印出来
We need to draw out Ultron.
不不不不
No, no, no, no.
别来烦我
Leave me alone!
他肯定是不开心了
Well, he's definitely unhappy.
我尽量不让他开心起来
I'm gonna try and keep him that way.
你不是他对手的  队长
You're not a match for him, Cap.
谢了  巴顿
Thanks, Barton.
知道摇篮里有什么吗
You know what's in that cradle?
改变世界的力量
The power to make real change.
那让你恐惧
And that terrifies you.
反正不是什么慰藉
I wouldn't call it a comfort.
够了
Stop it.
可以着陆  四  三...
We got a window. Four, three...
揍死他
Give him hell.
总是我来收拾你们的烂摊子
I'm always picking up after you boys.
他们在往立交桥下走  我打不到
They're heading under the overpass. I've got no shot.
那边
Which way?
右转急弯
Hard right.
现在
Now.
让开  借光  抱歉  借光
Out of the way! Coming through! Sorry, coming through!
来啊
Come on!
-克林特  能引开守卫吗  -我试试
- Clint, can you draw out the guards? - Let's find out.
他们回你那边了
They're heading back towards you.
不管你要干什么  得抓紧了
So whatever you're gonna do, do it now.
我要进去了  队长  引开他注意力
I'm going in. Cap, can you keep him occupied?
你以为我在干吗啊
What do you think I've been doing?
好了  包裹在空中
Okay, package is airborne.
目标视线良好
I have a clean shot.
不行  我还在车里
Negative. I am still in the truck.
-你是要干...  -准备好
- What the hell are you... - Just be ready.
我带着包裹去找你
I'm sending the package to you.
要我怎么接
How do you want me to take it?
还是别知道的好
You might wish you hadn't asked that.
别这样
Please, don't do this.
我们还有得选吗
What choice do we have?
他消失了
I lost him!
朝你那去了
He's headed your way!
小娜  该走了
Nat, we gotta go.
小娜
Nat!
队长  看到小娜了吗
Cap, you see Nat?
拿到包裹赶紧给斯塔克  快走
If you have the package, get it to Stark! Go!
看到小娜了吗
Do you have eyes on Nat?
快走
Go!
该死
Damn it.
路上有平民
Civilians in our path.
能让车停下来吗
Can you stop this thing?
我没事
I'm fine.
待一分钟就好
I just need to take a minute.
一分钟都不想给你
I'm very tempted not to give you one.
拿到摇篮了吗
The Cradle. Did you get it?
斯塔克会处理的
Stark will take care of it.
不会的
No, he won't.
你不知道怎么回事  斯塔克没疯
You don't know what you're talking about. Stark's not crazy.
他会尽一切能力弥补的
He will do anything to make things right.
斯塔克  收到没
Stark, come in.
斯塔克
Stark.
有人收到吗
Anyone on comms.
奥创不知道拯救世界
Ultron can't tell the difference
和毁灭世界有什么区别
between saving the world and destroying it.
你以为他是跟谁学的
Where do you think he gets that?
-小娜有消息吗  -还没有
- Anything on Nat? - I haven't heard.
她肯定还活着  不然奥创肯定拼命嘲讽咱们
But she's alive, or Ultron would be rubbing our faces in it.
密不透风
This is sealed tight.
得修改程序
We're gonna need to access the program,
从里面瓦解它
break it down from within.
娜塔莎有没有可能
Any chance Natasha might
在互联网之外给你留了线索
leave you a message outside the Internet?
老派间谍那套吗
Old-school spy stuff?
我可以试着找找
There are some nets I can cast.
我会找到她的
Yeah, I'll find her.
我可以让组织瓦解
I can work on tissue degeneration
但你得先把赵这套操作系统废掉
if you could fry whatever operational system Cho implanted.
这个嘛
Yeah, about that.
不行
No.
-你得相信我  -不怎么信呢
- You have to trust me. - Kind of don't.
我们的盟友  保护军方核弹密码那个
Our ally, the guy protecting the military's nuclear codes,
我找到他了
I found him.
你好  班纳博士
Hello, Dr. Banner.
奥创不是因为愤怒追杀的贾维斯
Ultron didn't go after Jarvis because he was angry.
他攻击他是因为害怕他的能力
He attacked him because he was scared of what he can do.
所以贾维斯潜伏了起来
So Jarvis went underground.
分散开  抛弃了他的记忆
Scattered, dumped his memory.
但基本的协议还没忘
But not his protocols.
我把他拼起来  他才知道自己在哪
He didn't even know he was in there until I pieced him together.
你要我帮你把贾维斯弄进去吗
So, you want me to help you put Jarvis into this thing?
当然不是
No! Of course not.
我要帮你把贾维斯弄进去
I wanna help you put Jarvis in this thing.
这不是我的专业啊
We're out of my field, here.
你最了解生物机能了
You know bio-organics better than anyone.
你觉得贾维斯的程序
And you just assume that Jarvis's operational matrix
能打败奥创的
can beat Ultron's?
贾维斯还没有意识  就能在内部打败奥创
Jarvis has been beating him from inside without knowing it.
这是机遇
This is the opportunity.
我们可以造出完美的奥创
We can create Ultron's perfect self
不会想着灭绝人类
without the homicidal
还觉得是自己的优点
glitches he thinks are his winning personality.
必须这样
We have to.
我觉得值得一试
I believe it's worth a go.
我进了死循环
I'm in a loop!
又回到了从前
I'm caught in a time loop.
当初就是这里出的问题
This is exactly where it all went wrong.
我知道  我知道大家会怎么说
I know. I know. I know what everyone's gonna say.
但他们已经在说了
But they're already saying it.
我们是疯子科学家
We're mad scientists.
我们是怪物  哥们  得承认自己
We're monsters, buddy. We've gotta own it.
表明立场
Make a stand.
这不是循环
It's not a loop.
是走到了终点
It's the end of the line.
不知道你能不能醒
I wasn't sure you would wake up.
希望你能醒  想给你看点东西
I hoped you would. I wanted to show you.
也没别人了
I don't have anyone else.
我在想陨石  多么纯粹
I think a lot about meteors. The purity in them.
嘣  就完了
Boom! The end.
重新开始
Start again.
世界焕然一新
The world made clean
给新人类重建家园
for the new man to rebuild.
我注定是新人类
I was meant to be new.
我注定美妙无比
I was meant to be beautiful.
世界本可以抬头望天
The world would have looked to the sky
看到希望
and seen hope,
看到慈悲
seen mercy.
可现在他们只会恐惧地抬头看
Instead, they'll look up in horror
只因为你们
because of you.
你们伤害了我
You've wounded me.
这点不得不佩服
I give you full marks for that.
但是人类总是说  杀不死我的
But, like the man said, what doesn't kill me...
只会让我更强大
...just makes me stronger.
这套框架不匹配
This framework is not compatible.
基因编码已经完成了97%
The genetic coding tower is at 97%.
还剩三分钟  得赶紧把程序传上去
You have got to upload that schematic in the next three minutes.
-我只说一次  -一次也不说怎么样
- I'm gonna say this once. - How about "None-ce"?
-关掉  -不行  不可能
- Shut it down! - Nope, not gonna happen.
你不知道自己在做什么
You don't know what you're doing.
你知道吗
And you do?
她没进入你的意识吗
She's not in your head?
我知道你很生气
I know you're angry.
远不止是生气呢
We're way past that.
我不用变绿都能掐死你
I could choke the life out of you and never change a shade.
班纳  发生了这么多...
Banner, after everything that's happened...
将要发生的事才最重要
It's nothing compared to what's coming!
-你不知道里面有什么  -这不是游戏
- You don't know what's in there. - This isn't a game!
别  别  继续
No, no. Go on.
你说什么
You were saying?
皮特
Pietro!
怎么
What?
没预见到吗
You didn't see that coming?
电力损失过度
我换条线路上传
I'm rerouting the upload.
来啊  惹我生气吧
Go ahead, piss me off.
等等
Wait!
抱歉  刚真是
I am sorry. That was
奇怪
odd.
谢谢
Thank you.
托尔
Thor.
你帮忙创造了他吗
You helped create this?
我看到了未来[幻视]
I've had a vision.
所有生命的希望都被个漩涡吸走
A whirlpool that sucks in all hope of life,
漩涡的中心就是那个
and at its center is that.
什么   宝石吗
What? The gem?
是意识宝石
It's the Mind Stone.
六颗无限宝石之一
It's one of the six Infinity Stones.
宇宙里最强大的力量
The greatest power in the universe,
毁灭能力无可比拟
unparalleled in its destructive capabilities.
-那你为什么还...  -因为斯塔克是对的
- Then why would you bring... - Because Stark is right.
这下可真是毁了
It's definitely the end times.
复仇者联盟赢不了奥创的
The Avengers cannot defeat Ultron.
光靠自己不行
Not alone.
为什么幻视的声音像贾维斯
Why does your Vision sound like Jarvis?
我们重构了贾维斯的程序
We reconfigured Jarvis's matrix
创造了新的东西
to create something new.
新东西我真是看够了
I think I've had my fill of new.
你觉得我是奥创的孩子
You think I'm a child of Ultron.
不是吗
You're not?
我不是奥创
I'm not Ultron.
我不是贾维斯  我是
I am not Jarvis. I am...
这个我
I am.
我看过你的意识
I looked in your head
看到了大灭绝
and saw annihilation.
再看看
Look again.
她赞同顶个屁啊
Her seal of approval means jack to me.
他们的力量  我们的恐惧  包括奥创
Their powers, the horrors in our heads, Ultron himself,
都来自意识宝石
they all came from the Mind Stone.
这跟宝石的力量比都不算什么
And they're nothing compared to what it can unleash.
-可如果在我们这边...  -是吗
- But with it on our side... - Is it?
你是吗
Are you?
在我们这边
On our side?
我觉得没那么简单
I don't think it's that simple.
最好赶紧弄简单点
Well, it better get real simple real soon.
我站在生命这边
I am on the side of life.
奥创不是
Ultron isn't.
他会毁灭生命
He will end it all.
他在等什么
What's he waiting for?
-你  -在哪
- You. - Where?
索科威亚
Sokovia.
小娜也关在那
He's got Nat there, too.
如果我们看错了你
If we're wrong about you,
如果你是奥创造出来的怪物
if you're the monster that Ultron made you to be...
你会怎么做
What will you do?
我不想杀奥创
I don't want to kill Ultron.
他很独特  很痛苦
He's unique and he's in pain.
但那痛苦会毁灭地球
But that pain will roll over the Earth.
所以必须毁灭他
So, he must be destroyed.
他的每一个形态  留下的每一丝痕迹
Every form he's built, every trace of his presence on the net.
现在就得行动
We have to act now.
这点我们光靠自己是做不到的
And not one of us can do it without the others.
我也许是个怪物
Maybe I am a monster.
我是不是自己也不会知道
I don't think I'd know if I were one.
我不是你们
I'm not what you are,
也不是你们希望的那样
and not what you intended.
你们也许不会相信我
So, there may be no way to make you trust me.
但我们得走了
But we need to go.
好吧
Right.
漂亮
Well done.
三分钟
Three minutes.
准备妥当吧
Get what you need.
星期五
晚上好  老大
Good evening, boss.
我们不可能都撑过来的
No way we all get through this.
那怕还有一个铁人在  我们都输了
If even one tin soldier is left standing, we've lost.
肯定会流血的
There's gonna be blood on the floor.
我明晚是没安排
I got no plans tomorrow night.
大家伙先给我打
I get first crack at the big guy.
他等的是钢铁侠
Iron Man's the one he's waiting for.
没错  他最恨你
That's true. He hates you the most.
奥创知道我们要去
Ultron knows we're coming.
他们很可能已经严阵以待
Odds are we'll be riding into heavy fire.
我们早为这一刻做好了准备
And that's what we signed up for.
但索科威亚的人民没有
But the people of Sokovia, they didn't.
当务之急
So our priority
是疏散他们
is getting them out.
遭到袭击  全城市疏散  马上
We're under attack! Clear the city! Now!
快走啊
Get off your asses.
他们只想过平静的生活
All they want is to live their lives in peace.
可今天不行了
And that's not gonna happen today.
但我们可以尽力保护他们
But we can do our best to protect them.
我们可以完成任务
And we can get the job done.
查明奥创在造什么
We find out what Ultron's been building,
找到罗曼诺夫
we find Romanoff,
扫清战场
and we clear the field.
不让平民卷入
Keep the fight between us.
奥创觉得我们是怪物
Ultron thinks we're monsters.
觉得我们才是世界的问题所在
That we're what's wrong with the world.
这不仅仅是要打败他
This isn't just about beating him.
还要看他说没说错
It's about whether he's right.
娜塔莎
Natasha!
布鲁斯
Bruce?
没事吧
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
大伙都在城里  要开战了
The team is in the city. It's about to light up.
你没找到钥匙什么的吧
I don't suppose you found a key lying around somewhere.
找到了
Yeah. I did.
我们怎么办
So what's our play?
我是来护送你安全离开的
I'm here to get you to safety.
任务还没完成
Job's not finished.
我们可以帮忙疏散
We could help with the evacuation,
但有平民  我就不能参战
but I can't be in a fight near civilians.
你已经付出了不少
And you've done plenty.
我们的战争结束了
Our fight is over.
那就直接消失吗
So, we just disappear?
快走
Come on.
他在教堂  老大
Your man's in the church, boss.
他应该在等你
I think he's waiting for you.
来忏悔罪过吗
Come to confess your sins?
不知道  你有多少时间
I don't know. How much time you got?
反正比你多
More than you.
你打药了吗  打了一针振金什么的
Have you been juicing? Little vibranium cocktail?
你怎么...  我不想说"肿了"
You're looking... I don't wanna say "puffy."
你在拖延时间  保护平民
You're stalling to protect the people.
这就是任务  你忘了吗
Well, that is the mission. Did you forget?
我早超越了你的任务  我是自由的
I've moved beyond your mission. I'm free.
怎么
What?
你以为只有你在拖延吗
You think you were the only one stalling?
剩下的振金都在那
There's the rest of the vibranium.
功能不明
Function, still unclear.
这就是你的末日  托尼
This is how you end, Tony.
我这个时代的和平
This is peace in my time.
走
Go!
快下桥
Get off the bridge!
快跑
Run!
奥创
Ultron.
我的幻视
My Vision.
他们真从我这夺走了一切
They really did take everything from me.
你自己定的条款  可以自己改
You set the terms. You can change them.
好吧
All right.
周五  幻视呢
Friday, the Vision?
成功了
Boss, it's working.
他在把奥创和互联网隔离开
He's burning Ultron out of the net.
这样他就逃不掉了
He won't escape through there.
你把我封闭起来
You shut me out.
你觉得我在乎吗
You think I care?
你夺走我的世界
You take away my world,
我就夺走你的
I take away yours.
周五
Friday.
索科威亚要飞起来了
Sokovia is going for a ride.
能不能体会
Do you see
这有多美
the beauty of it?
这种必然
The inevitability.
拼命登高  却只能坠落
You rise, only to fall.
你们  复仇者  就是我的陨石
You, Avengers, you are my meteor.
我除恶的利剑
My swift and terrible sword.
你们的失败
And the earth will crack
会毁灭整个地球
with the weight of your failure.
把我从电脑里清除  让幻视跟我反目
Purge me from your computers, turn my own flesh against me.
都没有意义
It means nothing.
登到尘埃落定
When the dust settles,
世上仅存的生物
the only thing living in this world
就只剩下金属
will be metal.
得走了
We gotta move.
你不变绿吗
You're not gonna turn green?
这种情况我必须保持清醒
I've got a compelling reason not to lose my cool.
我喜欢你
I adore you.
但我需要另一个家伙
But I need the other guy.
来完成任务吧
Let's finish the job.
这下算扯平了吧
I really hope this makes us even.
去做英雄吧
Now go be a hero.
振金做的核心有磁场
The vibranium core's got a magnetic field.
能让城下的土地聚在一起
That's what's keeping the rock together.
如果落下呢
If it drops?
现在的话  死伤成千上万
Right now, the impact will kill thousands.
高度足够的话  会毁灭全世界
Once it gets high enough? Global extinction.
楼里还有人  十楼
That building's not clear. The 10th floor.
好了
Okay.
进浴缸
Get in the tub!
有空中单位  向桥的方向去了
I got airborne, heading up to the bridge.
队长  有东西过去了
Cap, you got incoming.
来了都走了
Incoming already came in.
斯塔克  你想办法让城市安全降落
Stark, you worry about bringing the city back down safely.
剩下的人就一个目标
The rest of us have one job,
把他们都毁了
tear these things apart.
受伤了  就打伤他们
You get hurt, hurt them back.
没了命
You get killed,
撑住接着打
walk it off.
走走走
Go, go, go!
我怎么会造成了这一切
How could I let this happen?
你没事吧
Hey, hey, you okay?
都是我们的错
This is all our fault.
看着我
Hey, look at me.
是你的错  是大家的错  谁在乎呢
It's your fault, it's everyone's fault. Who cares?
你能应付这个吗
Are you up for this?
能吗
Are you?
我得弄明白  因为城市已经飞起来了
Look, I just need to know. Because the city is flying.
听我说  城市飞起来了  我们在对战机器大军
Okay. Look, the city is flying, we're fighting an army of robots,
而我只有弓箭
and I have a bow and arrow.
这一切简直太扯了
None of this makes sense.
但我准备回到战场  因为这是我的职责
But I'm going back out there because it's my job.
但我没法边干工作边哄你
Okay? And I can't do my job and babysit.
你做过什么  你之前是谁都不重要
It doesn't matter what you did or what you were.
出去了就要战斗  毁掉他们
If you go out there, you fight, and you fight to kill.
待在这也没事
Stay in here, you're good.
我会叫你哥哥来找你
I'll send your brother to come find you.
但只要你踏出去
But if you step out that door,
你就是复仇者的一员
you are an Avenger.
好了  聊得很开心
All right. Good chat.
是啊  城市都飞起来了
Yeah, the city is flying.
抓住你了
I got you!
看着我
Just look at me!
你没法救所有人
You can't save them all.
你永远不可能...
You'll never...
不可能什么
"Never" what?
话都不说完
You didn't finish!
你刚在打盹吗
What, were you napping?
托尔
Thor.
你真是让我烦
You're bothering me.
好了  这片安全
All right, we're all clear here.
这片还不安全
We are not clear!
差得远呢
We are very not clear!
好了  朝你那去了
All right, coming to you.
快点走  老爷爷
Keep up, old man!
没人会知道的
Nobody would know.
没人
Nobody.
"最后见到他时  奥创坐在他身上
"The last I saw him, an Ultron was sitting on him.
"是啊  会怀念他的  飞快的小混蛋
"Yeah, he'll be missed, that quick little bastard.
"我已经想他了"
"I miss him already."
先停火
Hold your fire!
罗曼诺夫
Romanoff!
谢了
Thanks!
反重力装置设定好了  会反转
The anti-gravs are rigged to flip.
碰一下就会全力向下
Touch them, they'll go full reverse thrust.
而且是飞速向下
The city's not coming down slow.
振金是核心
Spire is vibranium.
如果托尔能打一下...
If I get Thor to hit it...
装置会失效  但还不够
It will crack. That's not enough.
后果仍然很严重
The impact would still be devastating.
如果封住一端呢
Maybe if we can cap the other end.
把能量都逼回装置里
Keep the atomic action doubling back.
那会让整座城蒸发的
That could vaporize the city.
还有城里的人
And everyone on it.
下一波马上就来
The next wave is gonna hit any minute.
-有进展没  斯塔克  -没什么好主意
- What do you got, Stark? - Nothing great.
也许有个办法炸毁城市
Maybe a way to blow up the city.
不让城市撞击地球
That'll keep it from impacting the surface,
当然你们得先撤
if you guys can get clear.
我要解决方案  不是逃跑方案
I asked for a solution, not an escape plan.
冲击半径在不断增加
Impact radius is getting bigger every second.
得赶紧做出选择
We're gonna have to make a choice.
队长  这些人无处可去
Cap, these people are going nowhere.
如果斯塔克有法子毁了这...
If Stark finds a way to blow this rock...
先带所有人撤离
Not till everyone's safe.
是毁灭这里的人
Everyone up here versus
还是毁灭所有地球人  这不用算的
everyone down there? There's no math there.
这里还有平民  我就不离开
I'm not leaving this rock with one civilian on it.
我没说要走
I didn't say we should leave.
还有更惨的死法的
There's worse ways to go.
上哪看这样的美景呢
Where else am I gonna get a view like this?
你喜欢美景真好  罗曼诺夫
Glad you like the view, Romanoff.
美的还在后头呢
It's about to get better.
漂亮吧
Nice, right?
从箱底翻出来的  还有几个老朋友
Pulled her out of mothballs with a couple of old friends.
虽然有点灰  但还能用
She's dusty, but she'll do.
弗瑞  你个老混蛋
Fury, you son of a bitch.
嘴这么脏  怎么吻你妈
You kiss your mother with that mouth?
高度18000英尺  还在升高
Altitude is 18,000 and climbing.
准备部署救生舱
Lifeboats secure to deploy.
倒计时三  二
Disengage in three, two...
出发
Take them out.
这是神盾局吗
This is S.H.I.E.L.D.?
这是神盾局该有的样子
This is what S.H.I.E.L.D. Is supposed to be.
还不赖嘛
This is not so bad.
带大家上
Let's load them up.
长官  右舷纠集了数架敌机
Sir, we have multiple bogies converging on our starboard flank.
给他们点颜色
Show 'em what we got.
上吧
You're up.
棒
Yes!
这回可有的讲了
Now this is gonna be a good story.
是啊  但你得先活下来
Yup. If you live to tell it.
你觉得我自己办不到[握我自己的]吗
You think I can't hold my own?
这次成功了  我来握住你的
We get through this, I'll hold your own.
到你嘴里就变了味
You had to make it weird.
这群人之后还有50到100个
I got about 50 to 100 more coming in after this group.
快走  快走  走吧
Here we go. Here we go. Let's move.
快走
Let's go, everyone!
六号舱已全部  锁定...
Number six boat is topped and locked...
Lock, stock and barrel
全员...  到头...
Or stocked... Topped...
人已经满了
It's full of people.
敌机来袭
Incoming!
我的天
Oh, God!
你觉得你能救谁吗
You think you're saving anyone?
我转一下  早一点让这座城掉下去
I turn that key and drop this rock a little early
还是会死伤上亿
and it's still billions dead.
连你也不能阻止
Even you can't stop that.
我是托尔  奥丁之子
I am Thor, son of Odin,
只要我还有一口气...
and as long as there is life in my breast...
我想不出词了
I am running out of things to say!
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
这锤子重量分布得真好
It's terribly well-balanced.
要是锤头太重
Well, if there's too much weight,
挥起来会损失力量  所以...
you lose power on the swing, so...
有了  弄个热能护罩
I got it. Create a heat seal.
我可以...
I could...
我可以在底下让装置过载
I could supercharge the spire from below.
计算中
Running numbers.
能量够的话  热护罩可以成功
A heat seal could work with enough power.
-托尔  我有计划了  -没时间了
- Thor, I got a plan. - We're out of time.
他们冲着核心来了
They're coming for the core.
罗德  送其他人上救生舱
Rhodey, get the rest of the people on board that carrier.
好的
On it.
复仇者  该搏回命了
Avengers, time to work for a living.
-没事吧  -没事
- Are you good? - Yeah.
罗曼诺夫
Romanoff.
你和班纳不是打算鸳鸯双飞  一起隐居吧
You and Banner better not be playing "hide the zucchini."
别激动  铁头
Relax, shellhead.
还有人不会飞呢
Not all of us can fly.
-你什么打算[钻头]  -这就是
- What's the drill? - This is the drill.
让奥创碰到核心  我们就失败了
If Ultron gets a hand on the core, we lose.
你们就这点能耐吗
Is that the best you can do?
非得好心问一下
You had to ask.
这就是我的能耐
This is the best I can do.
我就想这样
This is exactly what I wanted.
你们所有人
All of you
对阵所有的我
against all of me.
你们怎么可能阻止我
How can you possibly hope to stop me?
老爷子说过...
Well, like the old man said...
齐心协力
together.
我事后诸葛亮一下...
You know, with the benefit of hindsight...
他们想逃离城市
They'll try to leave the city.
不可以  一个也不能放  罗德
We can't let them, not even one. Rhodey.
收到
I'm on it.
没让你走呢
No. I didn't say you could leave.
战争机器来了  就在...
War Machine coming at you! Right...
这是什么
Okay, what?
得撤了  我都能感觉到空气变稀薄了
We gotta move out. Even I can tell the air is getting thin.
你们去救生舱
You guys get to the boats.
我再找一下有没有漏的  一会找你们
I'll sweep for stragglers. Be right behind you.
核心呢
What about the core?
我来保护
I'll protect it.
这是我的职责
It's my job.
小娜
Nat.
这边
This way.
带人们上救生舱
Get the people on the boats.
我不能把你留在这
I'm not going to leave you here.
我能应付这个
I can handle this.
等大家都撤了再回来
Come back for me when everyone else is off.
一个也不能少
Not before.
明白吗
You understand?
我可是比你大了12分钟
You know, I'm 12 minutes older than you.
去吧
Go.
老大  能量已经远低于...
Boss, power levels are way below...
重新分配能源  只有一次机会
Reroute everything. We get one shot at this.
我知道需要干什么
I know what I need to do.
餐厅
The dining room.
把东面的墙拆掉
If I knock out that east wall,
劳拉就有了工作的地方
it'd make a nice workspace for Laura, huh?
周围挡一下
Put up some baffling.
她听不到孩子们乱跑的  怎么样
She can't hear the kids running around. What do you think?
反正你们总在厨房吃
You guys always eat in the kitchen anyway.
谁在餐厅吃饭啊
No one eats in a dining room.
时间不多了
We don't have a lot of time.
赶紧上救生舱
So get your ass on a boat.
大家伙
Hey, big guy.
太阳就要下山了
Sun's getting real low.
你安全了  没事的  系好安全带
You're safe now. You're gonna be okay. Buckle up.
保管好自己的物品  抓紧就坐
Secure your gear, find a seat.
科斯特尔
Costel!
我们之前一起在市场
We were in the market.
科斯特尔
Costel!
托尔  我需要你回教堂
Thor, I'm gonna need you back in the church.
-就这些人了吗  -嗯
- Is this the last of them? - Yeah.
其他人都上航母了
Everyone else is on the carrier.
如果这次成功了
You know, this works,
我们可能活不下来
we maybe don't walk away.
没准吧
Maybe not.
没有了束缚  我开心地玩
I got no strings, so I have fun
不被任何人约束
I'm not tied up to anyone.
快点  走吧
Come on. Time to go.
你没预见到吗
You didn't see that coming?
我的天呐
For God's sake.
-泽林卡  -科斯特尔  宝贝
- Zrinka! - Costel! Baby!
不  不  我没事
No, no, I'm fine.
没事
Fine.
今天真是漫长
It's been a long day.
旺达
Wanda.
你留在这会死的
If you stay here, you'll die.
我刚死过
I just did.
你知道什么感觉吗
Do you know how it felt?
就这种感觉
It felt like that.
托尔  等我口令
Thor, on my mark.
动手
Now!
大家伙  我们成功了
Hey, big guy. We did it.
任务完成了
The job is finished.
现在你得驾驶飞机返航
Now I need you to turn this bird around, okay?
隐匿模式追踪不到你
We can't track you in stealth mode.
帮我个忙  我需要你...
So help me out. I need you...
你怕了
You're afraid.
怕你吗
Of you?
怕死亡
Of death.
你是最后一个
You're the last one.
你本该是最后一个
You were supposed to be the last.
斯塔克想造救世主
Stark asked for a savior
却甘心得到个奴隶
and settled for a slave.
看来我们都让人失望了
I suppose we are both disappointments.
是啊
I suppose we are.
人类真奇怪
Humans are odd.
他们觉得秩序与混乱是相对的
They think order and chaos are somehow opposites
想控制自己无力掌控的
and try to control what won't be.
但他们的努力值得尊敬
But there is grace in their failings.
你没注意到吧
I think you missed that.
他们注定灭亡
They're doomed.
是啊
Yes.
但事物的美  并不在能否长久
But a thing isn't beautiful because it lasts.
身为他们的一员很荣幸
It's a privilege to be among them.
你真是天真到无可救药
You're unbearably naive.
这个嘛
Well...
毕竟我昨天才出生
I was born yesterday.
新复仇者联盟总部
纽约州北部
内特尼尔·皮特·巴顿
看  来见见小娜阿姨
Look! Say hi to Auntie Nat!
胖墩
Fat.
有个技术员标记了这个
One of our tech boys flagged this.
在班达海[印尼]坠毁了
Splashed down in the Banda Sea.
可能是昆式战机
Could be the Quinjet.
但是有斯塔克的隐匿技术
But with Stark's stealth tech,
我们根本搜索不到
we still can't track the damn thing.
好吧
Right.
有可能跳机游到了斐济
Probably jumped out and swam to Fiji.
他会寄明信片的
He'll send a postcard.
"真希望你在这"
"Wish you were here."
当初是你派我招募的他
You sent me to recruit him way back when.
你那时知道会发生什么吗
Did you know then what was gonna happen?
怎么可能知道
You never know.
只能先尽人事  再听天命了
You hope for the best, then make do with what you get.
我的团队不错
I got a great team.
没什么是永久的
Nothing lasts forever.
麻烦永远在  罗曼诺夫小姐
Trouble, Ms. Romanoff.
不管谁赢谁输  麻烦总是免不了的
No matter who wins or loses, trouble still comes around.
规则已经变了
The rules have changed.
这是个新东西
We're dealing with something new.
幻视是人工智能
The Vision is artificial intelligence.
-一台机器  -所以不算吗
- A machine. - So, it doesn't count?
举锤子的不是个人
No, it's not like a person lifting the hammer.
是啊  到我们这就不一样了
Right, different rules for us.
-他是个好人  人造的  -谢谢
- Nice guy. Artificial. - Thank you.
他能举起锤子  就有资格留着意识宝石
He can wield the hammer, he can keep the Mind Stone.
宝石在幻视那很安全
It's safe with the Vision.
这年头安全可不好找
And these days, safe is in short supply.
可是要是放在电梯里
But if you put the hammer in an elevator...
-锤子会被举起来  -电梯配不上呢
- It would still go up. - Elevator's not worthy.
我会怀念你俩的贫嘴的
I'm gonna miss these little talks of ours.
不走就不会
Not if you don't leave.
我没得选
I have no choice.
意识宝石是过去几年
The Mind Stone is the fourth of the Infinity Stones
出现的第四颗无限宝石
to show up in the last few years.
绝不是巧合
It's not a coincidence.
有人在下一盘大棋
Someone has been playing an intricate game
把我们当棋子
and has made pawns of us.
如果所有宝石都就位了
And once all these pieces are in position...
三个大同花
Triple Yahtzee.
你觉得你能查明怎么回事吗
You think you can find out what's coming?
能
I do.
除了这家伙
Besides this one,
没有解释不了的东西
there's nothing that can't be explained.
这人真不懂得爱护草坪
That man has no regard for lawn maintenance.
我倒是会怀念他的  你也会想我的
I'm gonna miss him, though. And you're gonna miss me.
男子汉这回要掉不少泪呢
There's gonna be a lot of manful tears.
我会想你的  托尼
I will miss you, Tony.
是吗
Yeah?
我是该撤了
Well, it's time for me to tap out.
我也许应该跟巴顿学点经验
Maybe I should take a page out of Barton's book.
给小辣椒建个农场  希望没人去炸
Build Pepper a farm, hope nobody blows it up.
简单的生活
The simple life.
你会有那天的
You'll get there one day.
我也不知道
I don't know.
成家  稳定...
Family, stability...
渴望那些的我75年前被冻进冰块里了
The guy who wanted all that went in the ice 75 years ago.
出来的是另一个我了
I think someone else came out.
你还好吧
You all right?
我在家里
I'm home.
你是想盯着墙看还是想去工作
You wanna keep staring at the wall, or do you wanna go to work?
那堵墙是挺有意思的
I mean, it's a pretty interesting wall.
你不是和托尼深情对视呢吗
I thought you and Tony were still gazing into each other's eyes.
怎么样
How do we look?
反正算不上传奇队伍
Well, we're not the '27 Yankees.
还是有几个大牌的
We got some hitters.
是不错  但还不是团队
They're good. They're not a team.
来调教一下他们吧
Let's beat them into shape.
复仇者...
Avengers...
好吧
Fine.
我自己来
I'll do it myself.